# **GRAHAM FISHER**

Address: 35 Old Orchard, Sandhurst, Cranbrook, Kent. TN18 5LQ. Phone: 07946176179 Email: graham.fisher@live.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self motivated, resourceful, experienced and extremely organised individual with excellent leadership and team building record who's a team player providing excellent time management and meticulous attention to detail for assessing operational needs and developing solutions to improve process efficiencies and save costs.

Energetic self-starter able to effectively problem solve and navigate high-stress situations to achieve goals on time and under budget with many years of progressive experience in various industries for several high profile companies.

Excellent at juggling multiple tasks and working under pressure with broad industry experience in Railway operations, Rolling stock maintenance processes, Finance, Marketing, Advertising, Customer Service, Logistics, Food hygiene and knowledge of many more.

## **EDUCATION**

#### GCSE's

Stantonbury Campus (1998) - Milton Keynes

#### **NVQ Level 2 - Business & Administration**

Intec Business College (2003) - Milton Keynes

#### **Certificate of Higher Education - Microsoft Office**

**E-Careers (2016) -** Advanced skills in all MS Office programs

#### **Certificate of Higher Education - Health & Safety**

Semester (2017) - Part of BTEC level 3 in Engineering

## **Certificate of Higher Education - Electrical Currents and Practical Electricity**

National Extension College (2017)

# SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

Advanced IT skills for MS Office, Adobe & bespoke software with super user access / Equinox / SOROS / Singlepoint / e-Docs / CACS / SMART Solutions / Audits / Technical document control (EDMS) / Minute taking / First Aider / Full & clean driving licence / Excellent written and verbal communication skills / Budgeting, finance & banking / Training / Quality control / Team leadership and supervision / Intermediate Spanish / Data Input / Database control / Meta data / Confidential data protection / Bookkeeping & Ledger Control / Reconciliation's / Adept at learning new bespoke software various

## ACCOMPLISHMENTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- <sup>o</sup> I've greatly increased productivity using my computer proficiency and creative problem solving skills by designing templates and spreadsheets that analyse data then use coding, macros and links to automate a lot of reporting processes and document production.
- ° I've vastly improved audit conformity by taking on a project to ensure all documentation is present and complete with all information accurate and electronically recorded which has been running successfully for years.
- ° I've raised large sums of money for several charities by organising and supervising various events and challenges such as project managing a music festival for Kent air ambulance, scaling mount Snowdon and arranging a public waxing of hairy men by beauty professionals.
- ° I've received several awards and recognition for helping out in other departments which is enjoyable and informative as I gain insight and appreciation for other departments by learning how their role in the company ties in with mine, which is a great learning curve.
- o I represented Hitachi at a rail festival in York, providing thousands of members of the public with informative and effective communication on what we do, why we do it, how we do it and where we're heading.
- I was treasurer for my local social club where I made numerous improvements and kept the books balanced and I still have a lot of influence over the running of the club due to being a respected member full of ideas.
- ° I regularly organise various social events around the country and abroad providing a full detailed itinerary and pricing within a budget which are always a great success due to a lot of meticulous research, calculations and flexibility to allow for any potential complications or alterations.

## WORK HISTORY

## **Team Administrator –** 04/2010 to Present Day

# Hitachi Rail Europe Ltd

- Ensure smooth running of operations in the absence of management by effectively communicating and advising staff of any updates or operational needs.
- Maintain the condition of the work site, materials and equipment while adhering to health, safety, environmental & quality practices in the workplace
- Communicate on-call rosters and update the shift roster to maintain correct records of staff attendance, absences and overtime.
- Collect, collate and record the train data and statistics via download dumps.
- Use bespoke software to raise, close and update work reports, update labour notes, book stock, track serialised parts, update unique campaign records and ensure all paperwork coincides with the work carried out for audit requirements.
- Maintain records of CCTV requests from the police and the customer and ensure hard drives are booked and tracked through the process until completed.
- Communicate process & policy updates upon request by ensuring printed and digital copies are available for all relevant staff and ensure they're all signed off.
- Assist Maintenance staff with reporting work, linking evidence to reports, familiarising them with new computer processes and helping with general IT issues.
- Assist with minute-taking for the daily management meeting and liaise with relevant parties regarding actions taken or required.
- Send weekly KPI's to the customer and update performance display with KPI's.
- Provide out-of-hours security support by controlling Gate Access systems and monitoring depot CCTV as well as greeting out of hours contractors or guests.
- ° Control the stationery for all departments and make a weekly stock order.
- Liaise with all staff connected to the depot including external contractors, cleaning staff, delivery drivers or any VIP's on the premises.

## Various Temporary Positions - 05/2009 to 04/2010

Whilst seeking permanent employment I worked in several temporary based roles which involved positions in customer service, market research, garden maintenance & repair, CCTV security installations, bar work and even farming as I like to keep busy and in work at all times.

## Smart Property Advertising Co-ordinator - 01/2008 to 05/2009

## Courier Newspaper Media Group / DMGT (Daily Mail and General Trust)

- Organise my team and our weekly workload then assign the work to the relevant person for completion within the strict deadlines that are set by the printers.
- Train clients on our web based software and discussing any specific requirements they have, making sure they receive the best possible service at all times.
- ° Ensure clients meet deadlines via email and phone and offer assistance when required.
- ° Send the adverts to the printers on time and ensure the quality is of high standard.
- Oesign detailed templates for a clients advert and solve any issues that may occur.
- ° Proof read adverts and make any last minute amendments when necessary.
- Provide feedback and suggestions for future software versions and test any bug fixes for current or updated versions and report on them.

## Senior Waiter / Bar Supervisor and Entertainment Consultant - 04/2006 to 11/2007

## Fox & Hounds Restaurant / Playa Park Hotel (Spain)

- Welcome clients, explain the products and serve them politely, efficiently and effectively by focusing on what each client.
- Investigate new recipe ideas, purchase and order new products, liaise with suppliers.
- ° Arrange entertainment such as quizzes and music and keep it relevant and up to date.
- Mentor and train staff, make them feel welcome and build their confidence and skills.
- ° Advise the head of entertainment on IT issues and the purchasing of equipment.
- ° Assist the MD with quality control within the hotel by reporting and rectifying any maintenance issues.
- ensure the smooth operation of live shows and entertainment by organising the music and testing the equipment is all in working order.

# **Porter / Supervisor / Logistics assistant** – 06/2005 to 02/2006

## **APM (Assured Packers & Movers)**

- Assist the logistics manager by mapping areas and booking the required tools, vehicles and man power needed for the jobs and manage the assigned team.
- ° Relocate people and their homes or businesses to new premises or move to storage warehouse.
- $^{\circ}$  Organise the storage of items within the warehouse and update the warehouse inventory.
- ° Organise time and staff to make sure the jobs are complete within allotted timescale.

# Reconciliations Clerk and Central Finance Administrator - 05/2001 to 05/2005

## **Abbey National PLC**

- Calculate tax and commission to generate invoices, create and store data reports, bank cheques, reconcile data reports and maintain accurate records.
- Raise foreign drafts, make wire transfers, raise and process journals, balance ledgers, transfer funds between the ledgers, setup and control staff visa cards.
- Confidently liaise with customers all over the world at all levels.
- Report to the CEO's and MD's with confidential items of great importance and process them after authorised.
- Work to minimum accuracy requirement of 98% with my average being 100%.